Marcel Breuer Papers
Marcel Breuer Papers
- Project Records, 1922-1982 (inclusive); 1940-1980 (bulk); 89 linear feet of manuscript material, 24,618 drawings, 6,160 photographs and slides.
  - MCCOMB HOUSE, Poughkeepsie, NY (1950-1954) [Residential, Single]
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence: Misc. Contractors and Manufacturers, Suppliers, Contractors and Service Providers (Box 73, Folder 15)
      - Financial Records I (Dec 1950-Jan 1952), Architectural Invoices (Box 73, Folder 16)
      - Financial Records II, Certificates of Payment (Box 73, Folder 17)
      - Office Records, Miscellaneous notes, correspondence and sketches (Box 73, Folder 18)
      - Specifications/schedules, Hardware Schedule with Supplement, Lighting Fixture Schedule (Box 73, Folder 19)
      - Transmittals (Box 73, Folder 20)
  - MCGINNIS HOUSE, Charlemont, MA (1955) [Residential]
    - Drawings, 4
      - Existing Conditions [11 Oct 1955]: Elevations and Plans., [Design Development Drawings]; 4; (originals) (Tube 1314)
  - MCGINNIS PENTHOUSE APARTMENT (NSIBP), Boston, MA (1956-1957) (not built) [Interior], (Alternate names: NSIBP/North Station Industrial Building Penthouse (Boston and Maine Railroad))
    - Drawings, 48
      - 20 Dec 1956-25 Sep 1957. Num. set: SK 1-24, 27-29 (Floor Plans, Sections, Elevations, Details)., [Design Development Drawings]; 27; (originals) (Tube 1115)
      - NSIBP. Jun 1957. Num. set: A1-A9 (Floor and Roof Plans, Elevations, Wall Sections, Window Details), [Working Drawings]; 9; (originals) (Tube 1115)
      - NSIBP. Jun-Jul 1957. Num. set: A1, A2, A4, A6, A7, A8 (2 copies), S1, S2, S5., [Working Drawings]; 10; (reproductions) (Tube 1115)
      - Fireplace Studies. 22 Jul 1957. SK-19., [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1115)
      - Kitchen Layout. 24 Jun 1957. SK-8., [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1115)
  - MCMULLEN BEACH HOUSE, Mantolooking, NJ (1960) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 146
      - Office Sets (multiple). Most with pencil marks/edits. Includes heating plan., [Working Drawings]; 47; (reproductions) (Tube 216)
      - Sketches. Rough sketches and preliminary designs., [Design Development Drawings]; 58; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Process drawings. Kitchen design and structural elements., [Design Development Drawings]; 8; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - 1st Floor Plan (1) (19 Jan 1959), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - 2nd and 3rd Floor Plan (2) (19 Jan 1959), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Elevations (North and South) (4) (19 Jan 1959), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Elevations (East and West) (5) (19 Jan 1959), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Details (SK1 - SK13). Structural details, framing details, roof details, finish details, dumbwaiter, matting layout, porch bench., [Working Drawings]; 15; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Foundation and Framing Plans (includes Site Plan). (1) (23 Feb 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - First Floor Plan. (2) (23 Feb 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Second and Third Floor Plan. (3) (20 Feb 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Elevations. (4) (1 May 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Detailed Section. (5) (17 Mar 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Sections. (6) (27 May 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Full Size Window Millwork Details. (7) (14 May 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Stair and Fireplace Details. (8) (9 Jun 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Kitchen and Bath Elevations. (9) (16 Jun 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Interior Details. (10) (n.d.), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Revised Kitchen and Bath no. 2. (11) (16 Jul 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - Misc. Details (includes stairs details). (12) (9 Sep 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 627)
      - First Floor. (2E) (14 Sep 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 627)
      - Second and Third Floor. (3E) (14 Sep 1959), [Working Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 627)
    - Photographs, 2
      - View of living room from upper floor, finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 128, Folder 12)
      - Northeast corner, finished project, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 128, Folder 12)
  - MERCK, SHARP and DOHME, West Point, PA (1981), (Alternate names: MSD)
    - Photographs, 45
      - Building progress (3 December 1980), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 6 (Box 132, Folder 3)
      - Building progress (3 April 1981), construction, detail; (black and white photographs) 39 (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - MILLS HOUSE, New Canaan, CT (1947-1948) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 14
      - Project Sketches (Small Graphite on Graph Paper Sketches), [Design Development Drawings]; 5; (originals) (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Topographic Plot Plan, [Site Surveys]; 1; (originals) (Tube 622)
      - Plot Survey, [Site Surveys]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 622)
      - Plans, Elevations, Framing, Details, [Working Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 622)
      - Heating Plan and Details, [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 622)
      - Plumbing Plan and Details, [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 622)
      - Hope's Windows- Window Details, [Shop Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 622)
      - Topographic Plot Plan (enlarged detail0, [Site Surveys]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 622)
  - MILLS HOUSE, ADDITION, New Canaan, CT (1951) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 7
      - Plans, Elevations, Sections, Details (including Furniture), [Working Drawings]; 5; (originals) (Tube 622)
      - Plans, Elevations, Sections, Details (including Furniture), [Working Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 622)
  - MODEL BATHROOM (1953) [Interior], (Alternate names: Model Bathroom for Tile Council of America/Bathroom for Tile Council)
    - Drawings, 11
      - Bathroom Plans and Elevations., [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 609)
      - 14 Jul 1953. Bathroom Plans, Elevations, Garden Wall Section, Details and Schedules., [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 609)
      - Bathroom renderings (with figure). Sketch/tracing and 2 prints (1 hand colored)., [Presentation Drawings]; 3; (originals) (Tube 609)
      - Bathroom Plans and Elevations (some hand colored)., [Presentation Drawings]; 4; (mixed) (Tube 609)
      - "Model Bath Room for Tile Council of America". 7 Dec 1953. Num. set: Interior Elevations, Plan. Frame Plans and Schedule (1); Details (2)., [Working Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 609)
    - Photographs, 3
      - Model bathroom with mosaic tile [dup of Slide 447] [Slide 790], finished project, interior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-14)
      - Model bathroom with mosaic tile. [Slide 447], finished project, interior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-5)
      - Model bathroom with mosaic tile. [dup of Slide 447] [Slide 715], finished project, interior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-5)
  - MOTLEY'S FASHION STUDIO, London, England (1936) [Interior], (Alternate names: Motley's/Motley's Dress Shop)
    - Published Material
      - Dress Showrooms Architectural Review (Dec 1937), 1 pg.; (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 21, Folder 11)
      - Dress Showrooms Architectural Review (Dec 1937), 1 pg.; (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 21, Folder 17)
    - Photographs, 1
      - Reception area and stairs., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 120, Folder 25)
  - MUNDIPHARMA, HEADQUARTERS AND MANUFACTURING PLANT, Limburg, Germany (1973-1975) [Commercial], (Alternate names: Sackler II/Defendon Pharma)
    - Drawings, 134
      - Expansion Study (29 Jun 1973): Nos. 01-02, [Design Development Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1444)
      - Site Plans (12 Jun 1973 ), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1444)
      - Design development drawings, [Design Development Drawings]; 62; (originals) (Tube 1444)
      - Design development drawings (annotated prints), [Design Development Drawings]; 11; (reproductions) (Tube 1444)
      - Design development drawings (May 1973-Nov 1974): includes perspectives, plan studies, sections, elevations, site studies, sign studies [23] [originals] [3] [prints], [Design Development Drawings]; 26; (mixed) (Tube 1445)
      - Interiors and Furnishings (Apr-May 1974), [Design Development Drawings]; 29; (originals) (Tube 1446)
      - Progress Prints (12 Jun 1973) (Nos. 1-3): Site Plans, Plans, Elevations, [Design Development Drawings]; 3; (reproductions) (Tube 1446)
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence (1972-1973) (Box 140, Folder 20)
  - MUSEUM FOR THE NORDRHEIN-WESTFALEN COLLECTION, COMPETITION, Düsseldorf, Germany (1974-1975) (not built) [Museum], (Alternate names: Dusseldorf Museum)
    - Drawings, 30
      - Topographical Map [film negative], [Site Surveys]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1265)
      - Presentation Set (Sheet Nos. 1-7) [n.d.] [German]: Site Plan, Floor Plans, Sections, Elevations, [Presentation Drawings]; 7; (originals) (Tube 1265)
      - print set of above (large format), [Presentation Drawings]; 7; (reproductions) (Tube 1265)
      - Misc. plastic sheets and prints for making presentation set, [Presentation Drawings]; 14; (mixed) (Tube 1265)
      - Isometric of East Elevation [n.d.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1265)
  - NEUMANN HOUSE, Croton-on-Hudson, NY (1953-1954) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 21
      - Plan [negative photostat], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Oversize 14, Folder 1)
      - Property Survey Plan, [Site Surveys]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 645)
      - Presentation Sheet: Site Plan, Floor Plan, 4 Elevations, [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 645)
      - Rendered Floor Plan, Rendered Diagrammatic Plan of Fieldstone Elements, [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 645)
      - Plot Plan, Floor Plans, Sections, Elevations, Details, [Working Drawings]; 9; (originals) (Tube 645)
      - Electrical Plan and Details (4), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 645)
      - Floor Plan, Sections, Elevations, Details [Blueline and Reproduced on Drawing Film], [Working Drawings]; 6; (reproductions) (Tube 645)
    - Photographs, 9
      - Side elevation., finished project, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 88, Folder 20)
      - Entrance patio., finished project, exterior view; (production image) 1 (Box 88, Folder 20)
      - Garden patio with view of bedroom. [color], finished project, exterior view; (production image) 1 (Box 88, Folder 20)
      - View toward Blue Exterior Wall [Slide 449], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-5)
      - Courtyard with trellis shadows. [Slide 145], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-5)
      - Garden patio with view of livingroom. [Slide 413], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-5)
      - Exterior Patio with Curved Stone Walls [Slide 53 ], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-5)
      - View of Colored Exterior Walls [Slide 435], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-5)
      - Partial Elevation [Slide 720], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-5)
  - NEUMANN HOUSE, POOL HOUSE, Croton-on-Hudson, NY (1973) [Residential, Single]
    - Drawings, 21
      - Prelim. Details, Test Boring Plan, [Design Development Drawings]; 7; (originals) (Tube 645)
      - Plans, Sections, Elevations, Details, [Working Drawings]; 5; (originals) (Tube 645)
      - Electrical Plan and Details (4), [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 645)
      - Signed Contract Drawings, [Working Drawings]; 6; (reproductions) (Tube 645)
      - Arcadia- Window Details, [Shop Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 645)
    - Project Files
      - Contracts (1972) (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: Architects, client, contractors (1972 to 1974) (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Financials: Change orders, billings, invoices (1973, 1974) (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: Contractor: Larchmont Construction Co (1972 to 1974) (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Memos (1972, 1973) (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Notes, sketches, budget estimates (1972, 1973) (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Product literature (1971, nd) (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Shop drawings (1972) (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Transmittals (1972, 1973) (Box 63, Folder 10)
      - Roof Repair for Neumann House (1964, 1971) (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, 37
      - Pool excavation and wall construction., construction, detail; (black and white photographs) 20 (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Drainage and sealant features., construction, detail; (black and white photographs) 16 (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Pool location at existing house., existing conditions, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - NEW ENGLAND MERCHANTS' BANK BUILDING, COMPETITION, Boston, MA (1964) (not built) [Commercial], (Alternate names: Boston Competition)
    - Drawings, 162
      - Diagramatic sketches. Site plans, floor plans, elevations, sections, wall panel and column variations, parking studies., [Design Development Drawings]; 84; (mixed) (Tube 625)
      - Diagramatic sketches. Site plans, floor plans, elevations, sections, wall panel and column variations, parking studies., [Design Development Drawings]; 50; (mixed) (Tube 634)
      - Typical Office Floor, 3-20 (P-1), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Typical Office Floor, 21-22 (P-2), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Typical Office Floor, 23-40 (P-3), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Lower Mechanical Floor Plan - 2nd Floor (P-4), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - Upper Mechanical Floor Plan - 41st Floor (P-5), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - Roof Plan - Cooling Towers (P-6), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - Ground Floor and Site Plan (P-7), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - Bearing Wall Panel Details (P-8), [Design Development Drawings]; 2; (mixed) (Tube 1091)
      - Non Bearing Wall Panel and Corner Column Details (P-9), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - North and South Tower Elevations (P-10), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - East and West Tower Elevations (P-11), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - Sections Through Lowest Floors (P-12), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - Basement Plans (P-13), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - Details Elevations of Lower Floors 9P-14), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - West Wall Sections (P-15), [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1091)
      - Situation Plan - Phasing Diagram (1), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Plaza Level Plan (2), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Circulation Diagram - Exterior Lighting Plan (3), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Floor Plans (4), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Elevations (5, 6) [dups], [Presentation Drawings]; 4; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Sections (7), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Elevation Details (8), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Typical Wall Details (9), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
      - Site Plan (SK1) (2 copies, 1 with color annotations), [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1091)
    - Project Files
  - NEW HAVEN RAILROAD, LOCOMOTIVES AND PASSENGER CARS (1955-1956) [Other], (Alternate names: ACF Talgo/Budd/Pullman Train "X")
    - Drawings, 72
      - ACF Talgo Train: Details of Drinking Glass Niche (SK. No. 1) [8 Jul 1955], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - ACF Talgo Train: Elevations and Color Scheme [31 Aug 1955], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - ACF Talgo Train: Hand Rail Assembly at Wheel Well [18 Jan 1956], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - ACF Talgo Train: Toilet and Vestibule (Void) [13 Jul 1955], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - ACF Talgo Train: Toilet Plan and Elevations [18 Aug 1955], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - ACF Talgo Train: Working Drawings [30 Jun 1955-3 Feb 1956], [Working Drawings]; 8; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Budd Train: Interior Perspective [2 Mar 1956], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Budd Train: Interior perspective [Mar 1956], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1178)
      - Budd Train: Location of Identification Light and Number (SK No. 1) [10 Feb 1956], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Budd Train: Working Drawings (Dwg. Nos. 1-9) [22 Jul 1955-7 Feb 1956], [Working Drawings]; 11; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Fairbanks-Morse Locomotive: Insignia and Painting Details [6 Jun 1956], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Fairbanks-Morse Locomotive: Partial Side Elevation [31 Jan 1956], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Pullman Train X: Baldwin-Lima-Hamilton Locomotive [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Pullman Train X: Baldwin-Lima-Hamilton Locomotive [n.d.] [photostat], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1178)
      - Pullman Train X: Color and Pattern: Exterior Skin [10 Jun 1955], [Design Development drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Pullman Train X: North Side Elevation: Color Scheme [16 Jun 1955], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - Pullman Train X: Presentation Sheet [n.d.] [photostat], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (reproductions) (Tube 1178)
      - Pullman Train X: Working Drawings (Dwg. Nos. ) [21 Jun 1955-2 Feb 1956], [Working Drawings]; 12; (originals) (Tube 1178)
      - All High Speed Trains: Comparative Data [n.d.], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - All High Speed Trains: Layout for Sizes [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - All Highspeed Trains: Application of Plastic Cup Holders to Seats (Dwg. No. X) [17 Oct 1955], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - All Highspeed Trains: Insignia and Number Details [5 Jan 1956-15 Mar 1956], [Working Drawings]; 3; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - All Highspeed Trains: Plastic Cup Holders [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - All Trains: Master Key: Color Designation [22 Nov 1955], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - Bag Rack Details (Dwg. No. SK 1) [19 Oct 1955], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - Bag Rack Details (Dwg. No. SK 1) (draft) [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - Commuter Coach: Preliminary Drawing: Plan and Elevation (Dwg. No. 1) [10 Oct 1955], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - Commuter Coach: Seat Plan and Window Studies [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 5; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - Commuter Coach: Walkover Seat (Dwg. No. SK1) [15 Dec 1955], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - Commuter Coach: Working Drawings (Dwg. Nos. 1-6) [11 Nov 1955], [Working Drawings]; 6; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - Reclining, Reversible Seat [n.d.], [Working Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
      - X-3 [n.d.], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1179)
  - NEW HAVEN RAILROAD, PASSENGER STATION (NEW LONDON, CT), New London, CT (1955) (not built) [Commercial], (Alternate names: New London Station/Passenger Station)
    - Drawings, 99
      - Rough sketches, structural studies for concrete shell, preliminary schemes for station (includes 3 process prints and blueprint plan of existing station)., [Design Development Drawings]; 32; (originals) (Tube 1126)
      - Passenger Station - New London, Conn. Aug 1955. Num. set: Key Plan Indicating Areas of New Construction and New Traffic Routes (1); Site Development and Bridge (2); Elevations and Sections of Station (3/3 "Obsolete"); Plan of Station (4/4 "Obsolete"); Elevations of Bridge (5); Plan of Bridge (6); Concrete Shell (7)., [Presentation Drawings]; 9; (originals) (Tube 1126)
      - Alternate viaduct schemes (schemes A and B), parking studies and preliminary site work., [Design Development Drawings]; 12; (originals) (Tube 1127)
      - Proposed Federal Street Viaduct and Parking, Scheme 1. 25 May 1955. Num. set: [PR.1] to PR.9 (no PR.7). [reproduction prints with hand coloring and pencil annotations], [Presentation Drawings]; 8; (mixed) (Tube 1127)
      - Presentation Set: Site Development. 22 Jun 1955. Num. set: D1 to D12. [reproduction prints with hand coloring and pencil annotations], [Presentation Drawings]; 13; (mixed) (Tube 1127)
      - Proposed Parking Facilities Plan. 25 Oct 1954. [includes typed cover sheet], [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1127)
      - Passenger Station - New London, Conn. Aug 1955. Num. set: Key Plan Indicating Areas of New Construction and New Traffic Routes (1); Site Development and Bridge (2); Elevations and Sections of Station (3); Plan of Station (4); Elevations of Bridge (5); Plan of Bridge (6); Concrete Shell (7); "Proposed Viaduct at Present R.R. Sta at New London". Apr 1955. Sheme D [attached to set with tape]. [reproduction prints with hand coloring and pencil annotations], [Presentation Drawings]; 8; (reproductions) (Tube 1127)
      - Property Affected by New Viaduct and Re-Location of C.V.R.R. Track. 7 Sep 1955. [original drawing and blueprint], [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (mixed) (Tube 1127)
      - Property, R.R. Track and Pavement Adjustments in Connection with New Overpass and Parking Facilities. 9 Dec 1955. SK-1. [original drawing and hand colored print], [Presentation Drawings]; 3; (mixed) (Tube 1127)
      - Site work sketches, maps and survey material of New London and project site, alternate viaduct schemes (schemes B and C)., [Design Development Drawings]; 11; (reproductions) (Tube 1127)
    - Project Files
  - NEW HAVEN RAILROAD, PASSENGER STATION (RYE, NY), Rye, NY (1955-1956) (not built) [Other], (Alternate names: Rye Passenger Station)
    - Drawings, 32
      - Preliminary Site Plan, [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1144)
      - Dimensions of No.11 Phone Booth: Reproduced Product specs. With Pencil Annotations, [Other Drawings]; 1; (hybrids) (Tube 1144)
      - Rendered Perspective of Station Building with View Through Toward Platform, [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1144)
      - Traffic Pattern Studies for Circulation around Station: Schemes No. 1-3, [Design Development Drawings]; 6; (hybrids) (Tube 1144)
      - Rendered Perspective of Station Building with View Through Toward Platform, [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1144)
      - Prelim. Sketch: Full Scale Details of Furring on Metal Partitions in Executive Offices, [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1144)
      - 9 Jan. 1956; SK1: Details of Furring on Metal Partitions in Executive Offices, [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1144)
      - 26 April 1956; Preliminary Plan, [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (originals) (Tube 1144)